<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<appendix xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="app_community_support">
    <?dbhtml stop-chunking?>
    <title>Community support</title>
    <para>Many resources are available to help you run and use OpenDaylight. Members of the
        OpenDaylight community can answer questions and help with bug suspicions. We are constantly
        improving and adding to the main features of OpenDaylight, but if you have any problems, do
        not hesitate to ask. Use the following resources to get OpenDaylight support and
        troubleshoot your existing installations.</para>
    <section xml:id="app_community_support-documentation">
        <title>Documentation</title>
        <para>For the available OpenDaylight documentation, see <link
                xlink:href="http://docs.openstack.org">docs.opendaylight.org</link>.</para>
        <para>The following books explain how to install and operate OpenDaylight SDN Controller: </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <link
                        xlink:href="http://docs.openstack.org/trunk/install-guide/install/apt-debian/content/"
                            ><citetitle>Installation Guide</citetitle></link>
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <link xlink:href="http://docs.openstack.org/user-guide/content/"><citetitle>End
                            User Guide</citetitle></link>
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <link xlink:href="http://docs.openstack.org/cli-reference/content/"
                            ><citetitle>Command Line Interface Reference</citetitle></link>
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>The following documentation provides reference and guidance information for the
            OpenStack APIs:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para><link xlink:href="http://api.openstack.org/api-ref.html">OpenDaylight API
                        Reference</link></para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="app_community_support-mailing-lists">
        <title>OpenDaylight mailing lists</title>
        <para>A great way to get answers and insights is to post your question or problematic
            scenario to the OpenStack mailing list. You can learn from and help others who might
            have similar issues. To subscribe or view the archives, go to <link
                xlink:href="https://lists.opendaylight.org/mailman/listinfo"
                >https://lists.opendaylight.org/mailman/listinfo</link>. You might be interested in
            the other mailing lists for specific projects or development, which you can find <link
                xlink:href="https://lists.opendaylight.org/mailman/listinfo">on the wiki</link>.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="app_community_support-wiki">
        <title>The OpenDaylight wiki</title>
        <para>The <link xlink:href="https://wiki.opendaylight.org/view/Main_Page">OpenDaylight
                wiki</link> contains a broad range of topics but some of the information can be
            difficult to find or is a few pages deep. Fortunately, the wiki search feature enables
            you to search by title or content. If you search for specific information, such as about
            networking or nova, you can find lots of relevant material. More is being added all the
            time, so be sure to check back often. You can find the search box in the upper right
            corner of any OpenDaylight wiki page.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="app_community_support-bugs-area">
        <title>Bugzilla Bugs</title>
        <para>The OpenDaylight community values your set up and testing efforts and wants your
            feedback. To log a bug, you must sign up for an OpenDaylight account at <link
                xlink:href="https://launchpad.net/+login">https://launchpad.net/+login</link>. You
            can view existing bugs and report bugs in the Bugzilla bug tracker at <link
                xlink:href="https://bugs.opendaylight.org/"/>. Use the search feature to determine
            whether the bug has already been reported or even better, already fixed. If it still
            seems like your bug is unreported, fill out a bug report.</para>
        <para>Some tips:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Give a clear, concise summary!</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Provide as much detail as possible in the description. Paste in your command
                    output or stack traces, links to screen shots, and so on.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Be sure to include the software and package versions that you are using,
                    especially if you are using a development branch, such as, <literal>"Hydrogen
                        release" vs git commit
                    bc79c3ecc55929bac585d04a03475b72e06a3208</literal>.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Any deployment specific information is helpful, such as Ubuntu 12.04 or
                    multi-node install.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="app_support-irc_channel">
        <title>The OpenDaylight IRC channel</title>
        <para>The OpenDaylight community is usually available in the #opendaylight IRC channel on
            the Freenode network. You can hang out, ask questions, or get immediate feedback for
            urgent and pressing issues. To install an IRC client or use a browser-based client, go
            to <link xlink:href="http://webchat.freenode.net">http://webchat.freenode.net/</link>.
            You can also use Colloquy (Mac OS X, <link xlink:href="http://colloquy.info/"
                >http://colloquy.info/</link>), mIRC (Windows, <link
                xlink:href="http://www.mirc.com/">http://www.mirc.com/</link>), or XChat (Linux).
            When you are in the IRC channel and want to share code or command output, the generally
            accepted method is to use a Paste Bin. </para>
    </section>
</appendix>
