<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section [
 <!-- Some useful entities borrowed from HTML -->
<!ENTITY ndash  "&#x2013;">
<!ENTITY mdash  "&#x2014;">
<!ENTITY hellip "&#x2026;">
]>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="ovsdb_project">
    <title>Hydrogen Virtualization User Guide</title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Overview and
            Architecture</emphasis></emphasis></para>
    <para><inlinemediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../../../800px-Virt_edition.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Installation</emphasis></emphasis></para>
    <para>The installation instructions for the Virtualization edition can be found here</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline"
        >Configuration</emphasis></emphasis></para>
    <para>To configure OpenDaylight Virtualization edition using the OpenFlow 1.3 plugin, start
        Opendaylight Controller with the -of13 option. If you do not use the option, the controller
        will use the OpenFlow 1.0 version.</para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>To start mininet for the OpenFlow 1.3 simulation, use the following command:
                        <emphasis role="italic">mininet&gt; sudo mn --controller=remote,ip=a.b.c.d
                        --topo tree,2 --switch ovsk,protocols=OpenFlow13</emphasis></para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>To start mininet for the OpenFlow 1.0 simulation, use the following command:
                        <emphasis role="italic">mininet&gt; sudo mn
                        --controller=remote,ip=10.125.136.52 --topo tree,2</emphasis></para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Web / Graphical
            Interface</emphasis></emphasis></para>
    <para>The graphical user interface is the same as the one for Base edition.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="underline"><emphasis role="bold">Release
        Notes</emphasis></emphasis></para>
    <para>The release note for the Virtualization Edition can be found here.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">OVSDB</emphasis></emphasis></para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>OVSDB Integration is a bundle for OpenDaylight that will implement the Open
                    vSwitch Database management protocol, allowing southbound configuration of
                    vSwitches. It is a critical protocol for Network Virtualization with Open
                    vSwitch forwarding elements.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>OVSDB neutron bundle in Virtualization edition supports Network Virtualization
                    using VXLAN &amp; GRE tunnel for Openstack and Cloudstack deployments</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para>The below diagram shows the OVSDB architecture for Neutron: </para>
    <para><inlinemediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../../../800px-OVSDB-Neutron.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Feature list and other Project documentation can be found here</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The Design of the project can be found here</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Tutorial /
        How-To</emphasis></emphasis></para>
    <para>Introduction and tutorial for the project can be found here.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Help</emphasis></emphasis></para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Sign up for ovsdb-dev mailing list.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Join us in #opendaylight-ovsdb channel in freenode.net</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Visit us @ https://plus.google.com/u/0/+opendaylightovsdb/</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Virtual Tenant Network
            (VTN)</emphasis></emphasis></para>
    <para>OpenDaylight Virtual Tenant Network (VTN) is an application that provides multi-tenant
        virtual network on an SDN controller.</para>
    <para>The below diagram shows the VTN architecture: </para>
    <para><inlinemediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../../../VTN_APPLICATION_ARCHITECTURE.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
    <para>The User Guide of VTN can be found here:</para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>VTN User Guide</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Affinity</emphasis></emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Overview and Architecture</emphasis></para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The Affinity service provides an API to allow controller and higher-level
                    applications to create and share an abstract, topology and implementation
                    independent description of the infrastructure needs, preferences and behaviors
                    of workloads that use the network to "talk" to one another.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The detailed description of the project can be found here.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Programmatic Interfaces</emphasis></para>
    <para>Affinity API and implementation in OpenDaylight can be found here. Additional information
        can be found in the Affinity Developer Guide. </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Help</emphasis></para>
    <para>Sign up for affinity-dev mailing list.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">OpenDOVE</emphasis></emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Overview and Architecture</emphasis></para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>DOVE (distributed overlay virtual Ethernet) is a network virtualization
                    platform that provides isolated multi-tenant networks on any IP network in a
                    virtualized data center. DOVE provides each tenant with a virtual network
                    abstraction providing layer-2 or layer-3 connectivity and the ability to control
                    communication using access control policies. Address dissemination and policy
                    enforcement in DOVE is provided by a clustered directory service. It also
                    includes a gateway function to enable virtual machines on a virtual network to
                    communicate with hosts outside the virtual network domain.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Users interact with Open DOVE to create and manage virtual networks through
                    the Open DOVE Management Console (DMC) which provides a REST API for
                    programmatic virtual network management and a basic graphical UI. The DMC is
                    also used to configure the Open DOVE Gateway to configure connectivity to
                    external, non-virtualized networks.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The Open DOVE Connectivity Server (DCS) supplies address and policy
                    information to individual Open DOVE vswitches which implement virtual networks
                    by encapsulating tenant traffic in overlays that span virtualized hosts in the
                    data center. The DCS also includes support for high-availability and scale-out
                    deployments through a lightweight clustering protocol between replicated DCS
                    instances. The Open DOVE vswitches serve as policy enforcement points for
                    traffic entering virtual networks. Open DOVE uses the VxLAN encapsulation format
                    but implements a scalable control plane that does not require the use of IP
                    multicast in the data center.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The DOVE technology was originally developed by IBM Research and has also been
                    included in commercial products.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The below diagram shows an overall DOVE architecture:</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para><inlinemediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../../../800px-Opendove-arch.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The Hydrogen release review of the project can be found here.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Installation Guide</emphasis></para>
    <para>The installation instructions for the project can be found here.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Tutorial / How-To</emphasis></para>
    <para>Step by step tutorial for this project, including how to do zero day tasks, configuring a
        basic overlay, and externalizing the basic overlay, can be found here.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Programmatic Interface(s) (link)</emphasis></para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>OpenDOVE Northbound and Southbound APIs can be found here.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>OpenDOVE developer guide can be found here.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Help</emphasis></para>
    <para>Sign up for opendove-dev mailing list.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Defense4All</emphasis></emphasis></para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Overview and Architecture</emphasis></para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Defense4All is an SDN application for detecting and mitigating DDoS
                    attacks.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The below diagram shows Defense4All overall architecture:</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para><inlinemediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../../../../800px-D4A_in_odl.jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject></para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>An overview of the project can be found here.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Installation Guide (link)</emphasis></para>
    <para>The installation instructions for the project can be found here.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Installation Troubleshooting (link)</emphasis></para>
    <para>The installation troubleshooting of the project can be found here.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Configuration</emphasis></para>
    <para>The information for configuration of the project can be found here.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Tutorial / How-To</emphasis></para>
    <para>Introduction and tutorial for the project can be found here.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Programmatic Interface(s) (link)</emphasis></para>
    <para>Defense4All API can be found here.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Help</emphasis></para>
    <para>Sign up for defense4all-dev mailing list.</para>
  </section>
